Ames Family Papers, 1812-2012
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. INDIVIDUALS
  - GENERATION III
    - GENERATION IV
      - Activities
        - Cultural and philanthropic organizations
          - Metropolitan Museum: correspondence, 1971 (Box 113, Folder 11)
          - Museum of the City of New York: correspondence and report, 1973 (Box 113, Folder 12)
          - National Council of Women: correspondence, by-laws, and reports, 1974-75 (Box 113, Folder 13)
          - National Museum of Women in the Arts: correspondence and contracts, 1986-95, undated (Box 113, Folder 14)
          - New York House and School of Industry
            - By-laws and history, 1927-52, undated (Box 113A, Folder 1)
            - Financial materials
              - General, 1940-51 (Box 113A, Folder 2)
              - Mortgages: correspondence and contracts, 1942-43 (Box 113A, Folder 3)
            - Landmarks Preservation Commission: correspondence and memoranda, 1986 (Box 113A, Folder 4)
            - Men's Committee: correspondence, 1949 (Box 113A, Folder 5)
            - Merger with Greenwich House: correspondence and legal documents, 1949-50 (Box 113A, Folder 6)
            - Merger with Union Settlement: correspondence, 1950 (Box 113A, Folder 7)
            - U.S. Department of Labor: regulations, 1943, 1949 (Box 113A, Folder 8)
          - Planned Parenthood of Manhattan and the Bronx/New York City, Board of Directors: minutes 1957; interview, 1994 (Box 113A, Folder 9)
          - Smithsonian Institution, National Portrait Gallery, 1968-78, undated (Box 113A, Folder 10)
          - Young Women's Christian Association: agendas, minutes, correspondence, and memoranda, 1978-93 (Box 113A, Folder 11)
          - Other, 1953-93, undated (Box 114, Folder 1)
        - Clubs
          - Fortnightly Club: discussion topic and reading lists, 1987-95, undated (Box 114, Folder 2)
          - Other: handbooks and lists, 1958-94, undated (Box 114, Folder 3)
      - Writings
        - Essays
          - "Benjamin Franklin Butler of New England": typescript, 1979 (Box 114, Folder 4)
          - "Orchids in Bronze": typescript, 1983 (Box 114, Folder 5)
        - Books
          - The Ancestry of Blanche Butler Ames and Adelbert Ames (Box 114)
            - Correspondence, 1974-80, undated (Box 114, Folder 6-7)
            - Family trees and "Ancestry of Blanche Butler Ames," undated (Box 114, Folder 8-12)
            - Drafts, circa 1975-77 (Box 115, Folder 1-5)
            - Published copy of book, 1977 (Box 115, Folder 6)
          - A Collector's Recollections: George Arthur Plimpton
            - Correspondence
              - General, 1987-94, undated (Box 115, Folder 7)
              - Acknowledgements of complimentary copies donated to academic libraries, 1994-95 (Box 115, Folder 8)
              - Fan mail, 1994-95 (Box 115, Folder 9)
            - Distribution lists, 1994 (Box 115, Folder 10)
            - Financial information, 1993 (Box 115, Folder 11)
            - Typescript, circa 1992 (Box 115, Folder 12)
            - Partial typescript, circa 1992-93 (Box 116, Folder 1)
            - Published copy of book, 1993 (Box 116, Folder 2)
          - Jottings of a Harvard Botanist
            - Correspondence and financial information, 1972-87, undated (Box 116, Folder 3-5)
            - Reviews, 1979-80 (Box 116, Folder 6)
            - Typescript of forward and other sections, n.d (Box 116, Folder 7)
            - Published copy of book, 1979 (unfoldered) (Box 116, Folder 8)
          - Orchids at Christmas
            - Correspondence, 1975-83, undated (Box 117, Folder 1)
            - Published copy of book, 1975 (Box 117, Folder 2)
          - The Plimpton Papers: Law and Diplomacy
            - University Press of America: correspondence and contract, 1984-87 (Box 117, Folder 3)
            - General correspondence and notes, 1983-95, undated (Box 117, Folder 4)
            - Reviews, 1985-87, undated (Box 117, Folder 5)
          - A Window On Our World
            - British American Publishing, Inc: correspondence and financial information, 1988-95, undated (Box 117, Folder 6)
            - Other publishers: correspondence, 1987-88 (Box 117, Folder 7)
            - Design: correspondence, notes, and brochures, circa 1985, undated (Box 117, Folder 8)
            - General correspondence, 1987-94, undated (Box 117, Folder 9)
            - Reviews, 1985 (Box 117, Folder 10)
            - Photographs, 1973, undated (Box 118, Folder 1)
            - Typescript, circa 1988 (Box 118, Folder 2-4)
            - Typescript, circa 1988 (Box 118, Folder 5)
            - Galleycirca 1989
              - pp. 1-154 (Box 118, Folder 6-7)
              - pp. 155-313 (Box 119, Folder 1)
            - Photocopy of galley, circa 1989 (incomplete) (Box 119, Folder 2)
            - Published, unbound copies of book (2), 1989 (Box 119, Folder 3-4)
        - Speeches
          - Cambridge Rally (UK): correspondence and related documents, 1979-80, undated (Box 119, Folder 5)
          - Other, 1962-84, undated (Box 119, Folder 6)
        - Miscellaneous articles, clippings, lists, and notes, 1920-94, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Plimpton, Francis Taylor Pearsons 1900-1984
      - Biographical materials
        - General, 1909-91, undated (Box 120, Folder 2-3)
        - New Yorker profile, 4 Dec 1971 (Box 120, Folder 4)
        - Francis Taylor Pearsons Plimpton Memorial Lecture: correspondence, fliers, and lists, 1991-95 (Box 120, Folder 5)
      - Financial information, 1975-83 (Box 120, Folder 6)
      - Estate settlement
        - Appraisals: real estate and furnishings (Huntington, NY), 1983 (Box 120, Folder 7-8)
        - Federal Estate Tax Return, 1984 (Box 120, Folder 9)
        - Final Accounting of Executrix, 1984 (Box 120, Folder 10)
      - Posthumous donations to archives and libraries: correspondence, 1984-87 (Box 120, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence
        - Ames, Blanche Ames (mother-in-law), 1925-63, undated (Box 120, Folder 12)
        - Plimpton, Fanny (Ann) Hastings (stepmother), 1926-28, undated (Box 120, Folder 13)
        - Plimpton, Francis T. P., Jr. (son), 1981 (Box 120, Folder 14)
        - Plimpton, George Arthur (father), 1906-33 (Box 120, Folder 15)
        - Plimpton, Pauline Ames (wife) (Box 121)
          - 1925-49 (Box 121, Folder 1-9)
          - 1950-82, undated (Box 122, Folder 1)
        - Plimpton, Sarah Gay (daughter), 1963 (Box 122, Folder 2)
        - Others, 1924-90, undated (Box 122, Folder 3)
      - Speeches and writings
        - General, 1947-75, undated (Box 122, Folder 4-5)
        - "George Arthur Plimpton: The Collector and the Collection," Columbia Library Columns, Nov 1960 and Feb 1961 (Box 122, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1898, 1958, undated (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - Plimpton, Calvin Hastings and Ruth, 1958-92, undated (Box 122, Folder 8)
    - Robey, Harriet Stevens (1900-1993)
      - Biographical materials: obituary, funeral program, and eulogies, 1993 (Box 122, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence
        - Ames, Blanche Ames, 1950s-1966 (Box 122, Folder 10)
        - Plimpton, Pauline Ames, 1920-21, 1989, undated (Box 122, Folder 11)
      - Writings: books
        - Correspondence, 1992-93 (Box 122, Folder 12)
        - Bay View: A Summer Portrait, 1979 (Box 122, Folder 13)
        - No Luxury of Woe: Reflections on the Legacy of Ben and Sarah Butler, 1992 (Box 122, Folder 14)
    - Stevens, Ames (b. 1897): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, 1915-56 (?) (Box 122, Folder 15)
    - Stevens, C. Brooks, Jr. (b.1902): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, undated, circa 1940s-1960 (Box 122, Folder 16)
    - Stevens, Edith Stevens (b. 1899): correspondence
      - Ames, Blanche Ames, undated, circa 1960s (Box 122, Folder 17)
      - Plimpton, Pauline Ames, 1919-21, undated (Box 122, Folder 18)
    - Williams, Jessie Marshall (b. 1916): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, undated, circa 1950s-60s (Box 122, Folder 19)
  - GENERATION VI
    - Ames, Angier (b. 1947): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, 1960-67, undated (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Ames, Edward A. (b. 1933): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, n.d. (circa 1940s-60s) (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Ames, Oakes (b. 1931) and Louise Kimball Ames (b. 1932): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, 1943-1991 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Ames, Oliver, Jr. (b. 1945): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, 1954-65 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Davis, Ames (b. 1945): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, undated, circa 1950s-60s (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Davis, John P., Jr. (b. 1936)
      - Essay: "Oakes Ames and the Credit Mobilier": typescript, undated (Box 123, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, 1948-64, undated (Box 123, Folder 7)
        (includes correspondence from wife, Dee Walker Davis, and son, Randy)
    - Hoblitzelle, Olivia Ames (b. 1937): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames and Pauline Ames Plimpton, 1950-88 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Matthews, Blanche Davis (b. 1934): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, undated, circa 1940s-60s (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Miner, Phebe Stevens (b. 1923): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, undated, circa 1940s (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Myers, Harriet Robey (b. 1932): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames and Pauline Ames Plimpton, 1991, undated (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Pittarelli, Evelyn Davis (b. 1941)
      - General, 1958-63, undated (Box 123, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames and others, 1940s-64 (Box 123, Folder 13)
    - Plimpton, Francis T.P., Jr. (b. 9 Mar 1928)
      - Biographical materials: clippings and articles, 1951-89 (Box 123, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence
        - Ames, Blanche Ames and Oakes, 1941-68, undated (Box 123, Folder 15)
        - Plimpton, Francis T.P. and Pauline Ames Plimpton, 1989-93 (Box 123, Folder 16)
    - Plimpton, Susan Wadsworth (b. 1931)
      - Correspondence
        - Ames, Blanche Ames, 1955-64, undated (Box 123, Folder 17)
        - Plimpton, Pauline Ames, 1969-70 (Box 123, Folder 18)
    - Plimpton, George A. (1927-2003)
      - Biographical materials, general, 1930-2003, undated (Box 123, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence
        - Ames, Blanche Ames and others, 1930s-68, undated (Box 123, Folder 20)
        - Plimpton, Francis T.P. and Pauline Ames Plimpton, 1932-90, undated (Box 123, Folder 21)
        - Plimpton, Oakes, 1947 (Box 123, Folder 22)
      - Writings, 1960s-80s (Box 123, Folder 23-25)
    - Plimpton, Freddy (Espy), 1969-75 (Box 123, Folder 26)
    - Plimpton, Oakes A. (b. 16 Jan 1933)
      - General, 1963-77 (Box 123A, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence (Box 123A)
        - Ames, Blanche Ames, 1945-70, undated (Box 123A, Folder 2)
        - Plimpton, Pauline Ames and Francis T.P., 1950-95, undated (Box 123A, Folder 3-5)
          [see also SERIES II: REAL ESTATE - Borderland]
        - Others, 1970-94, undated (Box 123A, Folder 6)
      - Writings, 1966-2012 (Box 123A, Folder 7)
    - Plimpton, Sarah Gay (b. 4 Oct 1936)
      - General, 1942-90, undated (Box 123A, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence
        - Ames, Blanche Ames, 1940s-60s, n.d. (Box 123A, Folder 9)
        - Plimpton, Pauline and Francis T.P., 1940s-90, undated (Box 123A, Folder 10)
    - Robey, Nancy Hurlburt (b.1926): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, 1957-61 (Box 123A, Folder 11)
    - Stevens, Ames, Jr. (1929-2003) 1977-2003 (Box 123A, Folder 12)
    - Stevens, Edward B. (b. 1922): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, 1964 (Box 123A, Folder 13)
    - Strater, Blanche Frenning (b. 1929): correspondence with Blanche Ames Ames, 1953-56 (Box 123A, Folder 14)
    - Woodcock, Joan Ames: correspondence with Ames, Blanche Ames undated, circa 1950s-60; general, 1990 (Box 123A, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified documents, 1951, undated (Box 123A, Folder 16)
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Family history: coat of arms, undated (Box 124A, Folder 1)
  - Real estate
    - Bay View (Gloucester, Massachusetts)
      - House and views, 1893, undated (Box 124A, Folder 2)
      - "Mother Goose" garden
        - Circa 1932 (Box 124A, Folder 3-4)
      - Descriptive text, undated (Box 5)
    - Borderland (North Easton, Massachusetts)
      - House site, circa 1907-10 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Exterior, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Interior, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Grounds, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Butler Ranch (Colorado), undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - The Whim (Ormond, Florida)
      - Descriptive text, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - House, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Grounds, 1947-50 (?), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Sculptures by Blanche Butler Ames, Blanche Ames Ames, and other family members, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Villa Balbianello (Lake Como, Italy), 1954-61, undated (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Oakes Ames Memorial Hall and Free Library and miscellaneous and unidentified houses and properties, undated (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Individuals
    - Generation I
      - Ames, Jesse (1808-1894) and Martha Tolman (1813-1904), 1870, undated (Box 125, Folder 3)
      - Jesse and Martha Ames's residences, undated (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Butler, John and Charlotte Ellison, undated (Box 5)
      - Hildreth, Israel and his wife, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Generation II
      - Butler, Benjamin F.
        - Portraits, and funeral procession, 1950-1933, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - Monuments, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
        - Military and political, circa 1961-65 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Butler, Sarah Hildreth, 1845, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Generation III
      - Ames, Adelbert
        - Portraits, casual photographs, and funeral procession, circa 1853-1933, undated (Box 5, Folder 12-15)
          [see also boxes 128A-B]
        - Civil War, 1864-65 (Box 126, Folder 1)
        - Spanish American War, 1898 (Box 126, Folder 2)
        - With wife and children, circa 1891, undated (Box 126, Folder 3)
        - Military and political friends and associates, circa 1860s, undated (Box 126, Folder 4)
        - Residences
          - The Hill, Tewksbury, Massachusetts, undated (Box 126, Folder 5)
          - Other, undated (Box 126, Folder 6)
      - Ames, Blanche Butler
        - Portraits and wedding scenes, circa 1855-1932, undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
        - Pencil drawing of Blanche Butler Ames and Adelbert Ames, 1868 (Box 126, Folder 8)
      - Ames, Oakes Angier, undated (Box 126, Folder 9)
      - Ames, Oliver III et al., undated (Box 126, Folder 10)
      - Butler, Ben-Israel, undated (Box 126, Folder 11)
      - Butler, Paul, undated (Box 126, Folder 12)
        [see also Box 128B]
      - Ames, Adelbert: steel engraving plates of portraits, undated (Box 126A)
    - Generation IV
      - Ames, Blanche Ames
        - Portraits and casual photographs, circa 1891-1960s, undated (Box 127, Folder 1-3)
        - Eightieth birthday party, Feb 1958 (Box 127, Folder 4)
        - Artwork: copy and study photographs, 1915, 1981, undated (Box 127, Folder 5-6)
          [see also Box 139]
        - Photographs of orchids, 1964, undated (Box 127, Folder 7)
        - Lowell Airport, 1940 (Box 127, Folder 8)
      - Ames, Oakes, circa 1880-1950, undated (Box 127, Folder 9-10)
      - Blanche Ames Ames and Oakes Ames with children and extended family, circa 1905-10, undated (Box 127, Folder 11)
      - Ames, Butler, 1914, undated (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - Generation V
      - Ames, Amyas and Evelyn Ingeborg Perkins Ames, 1907-54, undated (Box 128, Folder 2)
      - Ames, Oliver and Ellen Moseley Ames, 1942, undated (Box 128, Folder 3)
      - Davis, Evelyn Ames, circa 1914, undated (Box 128, Folder 4)
      - Plimpton, Pauline Ames
        - Portraits and casual photographs, circa 1912-1940s, undated (Box 128, Folder 5)
        - Smith College and unidentified, circa 1922, undated (Box 128, Folder 6)
        - With family, 1935-83, undated (Box 128, Folder 7)
        - West Hills house, 1971, 1984 (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Generation VI
      - Ames, Edward and Sue Holtz Ames, undated (Box 128, Folder 9)
      - Ames, John, Jr. and Isabel Ames, circa 1950 (?) (Box 128, Folder 10)
      - Ames, Oakes and Louise Kimball Ames, undated (Box 128, Folder 11)
      - Hoblitzelle, Olivia Ames and Harrison Hoblitzelle, 1950, 1965 (Box 128, Folder 12)
      - Marshall family: unidentified children, undated (Box 128, Folder 13)
      - Mathews, Blanche Davis, 1955, undated (Box 128, Folder 14)
      - Mathews, Robert J. L. III, 1955 (Box 128, Folder 15)
      - Plimpton, Francis T.P., Jr., George Plimpton, Oakes Plimpton and Sarah Gay Plimpton (siblings), and families 1993, undated (Box 128, Folder 16)
      - Woodcock, Joan Ames, 1942-50, undated (Box 128, Folder 17)
    - Generation VII
      - Marshall family: unidentified "grandchildren," 1964 (Box 128, Folder 18)
      - Mathews, John P. and Robert J.L. IV (siblings), 1958, 1961 (Box 128, Folder 19)
      - Miner, Phebe Stevens and Joshua Miner: their children, circa 1960s (Box 128, Folder 20)
      - Plimpton, Peter and Susan (siblings), 1955, 1959 (Box 128, Folder 21)
  - Group and extended family, 1959, undated (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1964-65, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Ambrotype: Adelbert Ames as West Point cadet, circa 1856 [broken] (Box 128A)
  - Daguerreotypes: probably Paul Butler, undated; Blanche Butler as a girl, circa 1856; Adelbert Ames as a boy, undated (Box 128B)
  - Negatives: film
    - Oliver Ames, Pauline Ames, Harriet Stevens trip to Europe 1922; miscellaneous (Box 128C)
  - Negatives: glass plate
    - Installation of Ames monument, Hildreth Cemetery, Lowell, Massachusetts, undated (Box 128D-L)
    - Ames, Blanche Ames: photographs of orchid herbarium specimens; photographs of models and still lives for paintings (including woman on crucifix); photographs of paintings, undated (Box 128D)
      [prints of most are in box 127]
- SERIES V. CLIPPINGS
  - Scrapbooks, 1825-1902 (Box 129-135)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - From SERIES I: FAMILY HISTORY: Ames family genealogy, 1930 (Box 136)
  - From SERIES III: INDIVIDUALS
    - Generation II, Sarah Hildreth Butler: photograph, undated (Box 137)
    - Generation III, Blanche Butler Ames: filet work, undated (Box 137)
    - Generation IV, Blanche Ames Ames
      - Smith College scrapbook and loose items found in scrapbook, circa 1896-1900 (Box 138)
      - Art
        - Sketchbooks, 1899-1906, undated (Box 139)
        - Copy and study photographs, undated (Box 139)
        - Animals, undated (Box 140)
        - Color theory charts and sketches, undated (Box 140)
        - Sketches, miscellaneous, undated (Box 140)
        - Suffrage cartoons
          - Sketches, undated (Box 140)
          - Crucifixion sketches, 1917, undated (Box 140)
          - Reproduction posters for 75th anniversary of women's suffrage, 1995 (Box 140)
        - Davidia involucrata (Dove Tree), 1931 (Box 140)
        - Etchings with sketch studies
          - Woman with baby, undated (Box 140)
          - Fishing boat, undated (Box 140)
        - Landscapes, undated (Box 140)
        - Orchids 1931, undated; poster for "Orchids and Artists" (Smith College exhibit), 1991 (Box 140)
        - Portraits, 1905 (Box 140)
        - Oils, watercolors, and drawings, 1917-22, undated (Box 141)
    - Generation V, Pauline Ames Plimpton: A Window on Our World galley and dust covers, circa 1989 (Box 142)
  - From SERIES IV: PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Generation II, Benjamin Butler: photograph of portrait as governor (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Generation III, Adelbert Ames and Blanche Butler Ames
      - Wedding photo, 1870 (Box 143)
      - Spanish-American War, 1898 (Box 143, Folder 2-7)
      - Albums (2): Unidentified individuals undated; steel engraving plates (Box 144)
      - Blanche Butler Ames "photo book" album, circa 1900 (Box 144A)
    - Generation IV
      - Ames, Blanche Ames: album of family photographs, 1909, undated (Box 145)
      - Ames, Oakes: portrait, undated (Box 145)
      - Plimpton, Frances Taylor Pearsons, 1890, undated (Box 146)
    - Unidentified photographs of Generations I - IV, undated (Box 146)
    - Generation V, Pauline Ames Plimpton, photograph albums of travels, 1962-81 (Box 147-148)
    - "Claim of Sall's Battery, Captain Newton Knight, Tallahoma MS," 1873 (Map-case Flat file drawer 16)
    - Bay View: plot plans, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 16)
    - Adelbert Ames' Civil War citations, 1865-1901, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 16)
    - Borderland: floor plans, elevations, sketches, and aerial photographs, 1910, 1963, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 16)
    - Oakes Ames Memorial Hall: floor plan for toilet room (by Blanche Ames Ames), undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 16)
    - Floor plan of residence at corner of Commonwealth & Mass. Aves., Boston, by architect Edward H. Prichard (Map-case Flat file drawer 16)
    - Financial: Family Policy Group charts 1951; charts of ownership of various companies 1932 and 1952; list of bonds in Blanche Butler Ames estate 1921 (Map-case Flat file drawer 16)
    - Suffrage cartoons by various artists, 1915-16 (Map-case Flat file drawer 16)
    - Family trees, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
    - Real estate insurance policies, 1896-97 (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
    - Villa Balbianello: clipping, correspondence, and maps, 1989, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
    - Benjamin F. Butler: certificates and legal documents, circa 1893-1903, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
    - Adelbert Ames
      - Article in "The Puritan," undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
      - Honors and awards, 1898-1927 (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
      - Reconstruction: clipping and correspondence, and related documents, 1871-72 (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
    - Blanche Butler Ames: financial information and research materials pertaining to writings, 1928-51, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
    - Blanche Ames Ames
      - Galleys and research materials, 1963 (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
      - Lists of Massachusetts Senators and Representatives, 1931 (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
      - Articles about birth control, 1957-58 (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
      - Correspondence about birth control, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
      - Graph of birth rates, 1917 (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
      - Suffrage clipping 1867 (from Women's Centennial Congress, 1940) (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
    - Butler Ames: financial information, legislative documents, and drawings for Odorless Cooker, 1900, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
    - Pauline Ames Plimpton
      - Real estate: plans and maps, 1960s (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
      - Correspondence: Archibald MacLeish, 1969 (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
      - Travel: Chinese flag, 1976 (Map-case Flat file drawer 17)
    - Ames, Blanche Ames (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
      - Sketches 1919, undated (3 folders) (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
      - Portrait of David Fairchild, 1947 (reproduction print) (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
      - Portrait of Paul Mangelsdorf, undated (original charcoal drawing) (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
      - Suffrage cartoons: original pen and ink drawings, 1915
        - "The Dog Gives Them Away" (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
        - "Meanwhile They Drown" (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
        - "Progress" (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
        - "Two Good Votes Are Better Than One" (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
        - "Two Pedestals" (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
        - Photostats of above suffrage cartoons, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)
      - Suffrage sketches, circa 1915 (Map-case Flat file drawer 28)